Guide to the Loomis-Wilder Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- EBEN J. LOOMIS (1828-1912), 1828, 1845-1912; Series II; 7.25 linear feet (17 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Wilder, George G. (5), 1880 (Box 8A, Folder 101)
    - Wilder, Herbert A. (8) (Box 8A, Folder 102)
    - Wilder, John A. (43), 1858-1864 (Box 8A, Folder 103)
    - ________ (30), 1865-1870 (Box 8A, Folder 104)
    - Wilder, Mary W.F. Jones (3), 1868-1875 (Box 8A, Folder 105)
    - Williams, Gardner F. (1), 1890 (Box 8A, Folder 106)
    - Winter, William (3), 1872-1882, undated (Box 8A, Folder 107)
    - Wright, Chauncey (3), 1867-1868 (Box 8A, Folder 108)
    - Yardley, G.E. (1), 1883 (Box 8A, Folder 109)
    - Miscellaneous unsolicited business correspondence - printed (4), undated (Box 8A, Folder 110)
    - Loomis, Eben J.: letters to; unidentified brother (2), 1853-1855 (Box 8A, Folder 111)
    - Letters to EJL from unidentified; persons (5), 1857-1903 (Box 8A, Folder 112)
    - Drafts by EJL of letters to unidentified persons (17) (Box 8A, Folder 113)
  - Writings
    - Bibliography of E.J. Loomis: various lists covering 1872-1892 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Chronology of publication Wayside Sketches,Eclipse Party in Africa, 1894-1897 (Box 9, Folder 115-116)
    - Correspondence with publishers on various unidentified works, 1862-1899, undated (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Books, Published
      - Wayside Sketches: early collection of published articles and poems, contract and correspondence with Roberts Bros., complete handwritten manuscript, publicity and press notices, Circa1894, undated (Box 9, Folder 118-121)
      - An Eclipse Party in Africa: contract, correspondence with Roberts Bros., manuscripts, drafts and revisions, 1894-1896 (Box 9, Folder 122-124)
      - An Eclipse Party in Africa: publicity, notices and reviews, 1896-1897 (Box 10, Folder 125-126)
      - A Sunset Idyll: correspondence, lists of subscribers, copyright, bills, handwritten mss with some illustrations, page proofs, orders to Riverside Press, publicity material, press notices, etc., 1880's-1913 (Box 10, Folder 127-135)
    - Books, Unpublished
      - Bird book for children: incomplete draft, notes, etc, Undated (c.1899?) (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - Articles, Published
      - "The Vision of Memory," Cambridge Chronicle (Box 11, Folder 137)
      - "A Short Journey from the Present to the Valley of Youth" George-town Courier, August 5, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 138)
      - "The Elf-Hill of Georgetown,", September 16, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 139)
      - Review of "Chart of the World," by Berghaus N.Y. Express, 1872 (Box 11, Folder 140)
      - "My Brown Thrushes," etc. in Hearth and Home (correspondence and fragment), March 1872 (Box 11, Folder 141)
      - "A Story About Sparrows," Hearth and Home (payment only), September 1872 (Box 11, Folder 142)
      - Letters on trip through West Va. Georgetown Courier, October 19; November 9, 16, 23, 1872 (Box 11, Folder 143)
      - "Spring Clearing," Sunday Monday Chronicle, June 29, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 144)
      - "Cooney Brooks and Showers," Sunday Morning Chronicle, July 27, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 145)
      - "Loughborough's Mill," Sunday Morning Chronicle, August 10, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - "Bladensburg and by the Way," Sunday Morning Chronicle, September 7, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      - "Persimmons: A Winter Sketch," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, January 11, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 148)
      - "A Sunday Walk from Buchanan to the Peaks of Otter," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, January 18, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 149)
      - "A Gallop to Mayport Mills," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, January 25, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 150)
      - "The Coming of Spring," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, February 8, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - "A Visit to Ashfield," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, February 22, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      - "From Middle Age to Youth — Was It a Fact?,", November 12, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 153)
      - Note on Sumner's Funeral, Circa1874 (Box 11, Folder 154)
      - "The Washington Monument," N.Y.Tribune, February 1876 (Box 11, Folder 155)
      - "The Coming of Autumn," Christian Union, August 9, 1876 (Box 11, Folder 156)
      - Review of "A Colored Astronomer," by Tyson and Kirk in The Critic, July 22, 1886 (Box 11, Folder 157)
      - "My Neighbors in the Attic," Christian Union, July 22, 1886. (Box 11, Folder 158)
      - "Glen People: A Fantasy," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, March 1889 (Box 11, Folder 159)
      - "Korean Legation," Home Magazine, March 1889 (Box 11, Folder 160)
      - "Astronomical Distances," Home Magazine, March 1889 (Box 11, Folder 161)
        See also: folio 35
      - "The Modern Way," Home Magazine, May 1889 (Box 11, Folder 162)
      - "Weldon Bill," Home Magazine, May 1889 (Box 11, Folder 163)
      - "West African Sights and Impressionsm," The Nation, March 6, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 164)
      - "Ascension," The Nation, June 12, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 165)
      - "St. Helena Nooks," The Independent, September 18, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 166)
      - "Kimberly and Its Diamonds," Illustrated American, November 1, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 167)
      - "Lynn's Natural Advantages," Letter to Editor of Lynn (Mass.) Daily Item, November 1, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 168)
      - "A Son of Derry," Letter to Editor of (N.H.) Derry, September 18, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 169)
      - Review of "The People of Mars" by C. Talman, in Monthly Weather Review, December 1900 (Box 11, Folder 170)
      - "St. Helena and Its Ladder," Home Magazine, July 1904 (Box 11, Folder 171)
      - "Elmina," Home Magazine, November 1904 (Box 11, Folder 172)
      - "Mr. Rouzee,", undated (Box 11, Folder 173)
      - "A Visit to the Sugarloaf Mountain" (2 parts), undated (Box 11, Folder 174)
      - "Wood Roads,", undated (Box 11, Folder 175)
      - Letters to editors, undated (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Articles, Unpublished
      - Letters to editors, 1868, undated (Box 11, Folder 177)
      - "Florida as a Winter Resort for Birds,", undated (Box 11, Folder 178)
      - "On foot from Washington to the peaks of Otter,", 1873 (Box 11, Folder 179)
      - "Spring Flowers,", January 1881 (Box 11, Folder 180)
      - "Artificial Production of Rain,", 1833-1834 (Box 11, Folder 181)
      - "Our October Vacation,", 1888 (Box 11, Folder 182)
      - "On Building in Washington, D.C.,", 1888, undated (Box 12, Folder 183)
      - "The Nebular Hypothesis,", by May 1889 (Box 12, Folder 184)
      - Review of Poems by Emily Dickinson, 1890 (Box 12, Folder 185)
      - "A Salem Collection of Art Curios and Relics,", (c.1890) (Box 12, Folder 186)
      - "A Day at Green Mountain, Ascension Island,", April 10, 1890 (Box 12, Folder 187)
      - "Ascension: Green Mountain, Wide Awake Fair,", (By December 1890) (Box 12, Folder 188)
      - "From 'Tartar Stairs' to Green Mountain,", (1890 or later) (Box 12, Folder 189)
      - Writing on Horta Fazal, Azores, Undated (1890 or later) (Box 12, Folder 190)
      - Capetown, Kimberly and Diamond Mines — various drafts and notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 191)
      - "St. Helena Days," "My Visit to Longwood by Another Road,", undated (Box 12, Folder 192)
      - Writings on St. Helena and Napoleon, undated (Box 12, Folder 193)
      - "Sea and Mountains,", February 1892 (Box 12, Folder 194)
      - "Woodland Tragedies,", 1895 (Box 12, Folder 195)
      - "An Innocent in Elmina, West Africa,", undated (Box 12, Folder 196)
      - "Bermuda: The Land of the Lily and the Rose,", 1905 (Box 12, Folder 197)
      - On Concord, Emerson, and Thoreau, undated (Box 12, Folder 198)
      - "Chance Thoughts,", 1873, 1877, 1881, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 199)
      - "Sunday on Parker Hill,", undated (Box 12, Folder 200)
      - "Arrowheads and Hatchets,", undated (Box 12, Folder 201)
      - "Some Things I See in My Morning Walk,", undated (Box 12, Folder 202)
      - "Observations from the Housetop by a Quiet Man,", undated (Box 12, Folder 203)
      - "Gathering Arbutus,", undated (Box 12, Folder 204)
      - "Saturday,", undated (Box 12, Folder 205)
      - "Pastures and Cow Paths" (including poem "Trailing Arbutus,", undated (Box 12, Folder 206)
      - "Story of a Pine Tree" (Allegory), undated (Box 12, Folder 207)
      - "In a Streetcar,", undated (Box 12, Folder 208)
      - Letters to Damascus from "Ayoub Hassam,", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
      - Review of Albee's History of Newcastle, undated (Box 12, Folder 210)
      - Review of G.F. Williams, "The Diamond Mines of South Africa,", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
      - Sermon on Text of Samuel 11:36, undated (Box 12, Folder 212)
      - Note on Collette Loomis, undated (Box 12, Folder 213)
      - Short drafts and notes on history of English literature, undated (Box 12, Folder 214)
      - General Essay on Astronomy, undated (Box 12, Folder 215)
      - "Sidereal Astronomy,", undated (Box 12, Folder 216)
      - Astronomical Subjects: short drafts and miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 217)
      - Autobiographical segments, 1863, undated (Box 13, Folder 218)
      - Prose: short drafts, 1860's, 1880's, undated (Box 13, Folder 219)
      - Prose: short incomplete drafts, 1860's-1886, undated (Box 13, Folder 220)
      - Publicity and printed material on lectures in chronological order, 1890-1905 (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Lectures
      - "The Sun,", October 1891 (Box 13, Folder 222)
      - "Kimberly and the Diamond Mines of South Africa,", October 1891 (Box 13, Folder 223)
      - "The Growth of Astronomy,", October 1891; October 1892 (Box 13, Folder 224)
      - "St. Helena and Ascension,", October 1891; October 1893 (Box 13, Folder 225)
      - "From Capetown to Kimberly, the Diamond City,", 1892, 1908 (Box 13, Folder 226)
      - "Picturesque Astronomy,", March 1905 (Box 13, Folder 227)
      - Rough notes for astronomical lecture, undated (Box 13, Folder 228)
    - Poetry: Collection
      - Small booklet, mostly unpub., Circa1850 (Box 14, Folder 229)
      - "Poems and Tales,", 1853-1855 (Box 14, Folder 230)
    - Poetry: Published
      - "After twenty-five Years,", March 1904 (Box 14, Folder 231)
      - "Anacreontic: Imitated,", March 1885 (Box 14, Folder 232)
      - "Aspiration," Christian Union, July 20, 1876 (Box 14, Folder 233)
      - "As Two Dewdrops,", undated (Box 14, Folder 234)
      - "At Night," Washington Sunday Gazette, Circa1878 (Box 14, Folder 235)
      - "The Brook," Georgetown Courier, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 236)
      - "Caged Mocking Bird's Lament," Georgetown Courier, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 237)
      - "The Cardinal Flower," Georgetown Courier, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 238)
      - "Concord," Forney's Cunday Chronicle, May 15, 1885 (Box 14, Folder 239)
      - "Cosmic Morning,", undated (Box 14, Folder 240)
      - "The Crow," Home & Farm, February 1, 1879 (Box 14, Folder 241)
      - "Dawning,", undated (Box 14, Folder 242)
      - "Death: A Vision," Christian Union, January 10, 1889 (Box 14, Folder 243)
      - "Deserted House," Cambridge Press, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 244)
      - "Dirge of Colette,", (1860?) (Box 14, Folder 245)
      - "Distant Mountains," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 246)
      - "Do You Remember?" Georgetown Courier, (1880) (Box 14, Folder 247)
      - "Dripping Spring"
        See: box 14, folder 251
      - "The Enchanted Water Lily"
        See: box 14, folder 258
      - "Evening Sonnets," Georgetown Courier, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 248)
      - "Field's Hill," Greenfield Gazette, October 27, 1888 (Box 14, Folder 249)
      - "First Signs of Autumn," or "Autumn Signs" Georgetown Courier, 1871 (Box 14, Folder 250)
      - "Forest Spring" or "Dripping Spring,", undated (Box 14, Folder 251)
      - "A Forest Walk" or "Georgetown College Walk" Forney's Sunday Chronicle, CircaAugust 1875 (Box 14, Folder 252)
      - "From the Grave" Georgetown Courier, Circa1853 (Box 14, Folder 253)
      - "The Gift" Home & Farm, 1882 (Box 14, Folder 254)
      - "Heart's Winter,", undated (Box 14, Folder 255)
      - "I Crossed,", undated (Box 14, Folder 256)
      - "Indian Summer,", December 1879 (Box 14, Folder 257)
      - "I Stand Upon a Hill, far far away…"
        See: box 14, folder 275
      - "Legend of the Water Lily" or "The Enchanted Water Lily" Georgetown Courier, (c.1877) (Box 14, Folder 258)
      - "Libraries" 2 sonnets to W.L. Shoemaker, Evening Post, December 18, 1877 (Box 14, Folder 259)
      - "Lines to a Very Young Lady," Forney's SundayChronicle, Sept/December 1875 (Box 14, Folder 260)
      - "Love Song: 'Time, Night in June'" Forney's Sunday Chronicle, undated (Box 14, Folder 261)
      - "Meridian Hill," Forney's Sunday Chronicle, 1875 (Box 14, Folder 262)
      - "My Dream," Home & Farm, undated (Box 14, Folder 263)
      - "My Friend,", undated (Box 14, Folder 264)
        See also: "Under the Tree," box 14, folder 294
      - "O Life, I Love Thee Moth" (sonnet) Georgetown Courier, November 13, 1870 (Box 14, Folder 265)
      - "Parody," Cambridge Chronicle, undated (Box 14, Folder 266)
      - "Parted,", undated (Box 14, Folder 267)
      - "Phantoms,", (1894) (Box 14, Folder 268)
      - The Pine: Two Sonnets" Home & Farm, 1878 (Box 14, Folder 269)
      - "Progress,", undated (Box 14, Folder 270)
      - "Questionings,", undated (Box 14, Folder 271)
      - "A Reminiscence: The Pines" Cambridge Chronicle, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 272)
      - "A Reminiscence: to E.L.,", b, d (Box 14, Folder 273)
      - "Setting Venus,", 1874 (Box 14, Folder 274)
      - "Sonnets: Youth, Expression The Mocking Wren,", 1871 (Box 14, Folder 275)
      - "The Storm," Home & Farm, August 1878 (Box 14, Folder 276)
      - "A Summer Dream" Forney's Summer Chronicle, 1875 (Box 14, Folder 277)
      - "Summer Sunrise,", undated (Box 14, Folder 278)
      - "Sunset" (sonnet) Forney's Sunday Chronicle, 1875 (Box 14, Folder 279)
      - "Sunset Idyll,", August 1875 (Box 14, Folder 280)
      - "A Sunset Picture" Sunday Morning Chronicle, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 281)
      - "A Thought" Christian Union, 1876 (Box 14, Folder 282)
      - "Three Gifts" Home Magazine, December 1888 (Box 14, Folder 283)
      - "Through the City's Ceaseless Noise,", undated (Box 14, Folder 284)
      - "To an Autumn Violet" Springfield Republican, 1855 (Box 14, Folder 285)
      - "(To) Colette" Georgetown Courier, April 13, 1872 (Box 14, Folder 286)
      - "To Colette,", 1885 (Box 14, Folder 287)
      - "To a Forest Spring,", (1878) (Box 14, Folder 288)
      - "To the Red-Eyed Vireo"
        See: box 14, folder 295
      - "To the Snowdrop,", (1885) (Box 14, Folder 289)
      - "Trailing Arbutus" Forney's Sunday Chronicle, April 1875 (Box 14, Folder 290)
      - "Trysting" ("I made a tryst with love…") Forney's Sunday Chronicle (Box 14, Folder 291)
      - "Trysting" ("When the sun…") Home Journal, (August 1875) (Box 14, Folder 292)
      - "Twilight on Lake George" Evening Star, March 1880 (Box 14, Folder 293)
      - "Under the Tree" Georgetown Courier, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 294)
      - "The Vireo" or "To the red-eyed Vireo" Forney's Sunday Chronicle, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 295)
      - "Waiting" (sonnet) N.Y. Independent, March 1876 (Box 14, Folder 296)
      - "Was It June?" Home Journal, (1885) (Box 14, Folder 297)
      - "Which Was the Dream?,", undated (Box 14, Folder 298)
      - "Who Is My Neighbor?,", 1878 (Box 14, Folder 299)
      - "A Winter Sunset" GeorgetownCourier, undated (Box 14, Folder 300)
      - "Youth" (Box 14, Folder 300)
        See also: box 14, folder 275
      - "1888-1889,", (1779-1789) (Box 14, Folder 301)
      - Dedicatory poem for The Triangle, April 1891 (Box 14, Folder 302)
      - Published poems, possibly by E.J. Loomis, undated (Box 14, Folder 303)
    - Poetry: Unpublished
      - "Afterglow," long autobio-graphical poem, undated (Box 15, Folder 304)
      - Poems with titles A-G, 1868-1906 and undated (Box 15, Folder 305)
      - Poems with titles H-P, 1869-1912 and undated (Box 15, Folder 306)
      - Poems with titles Q-Z, 1859-1909 and undated (Box 15, Folder 307)
      - Poems without titles, almost all undated (Box 15, Folder 308)
  - Personal and Financial Records
    - Mr. and Mrs. E. J. Loomis; biographical material on and publicity material, 1828-1912 (Box 16, Folder 309)
    - E.J. Loomis; Legal and personal records, memberships, diplomas, etc., 1850-1912 (Box 16, Folder 310)
    - Journals, Diaries, and Notebooks
      - Small diaries, 1845; 1859 (Box 16, Folder 311)
      - "Memorandum": a diary with original poetry, August-Nov, 1850 (Box 16, Folder 312)
      - Journal, 1851-1854; 1856-1862 (Box 16, Folder 313)
      - Notebook on weather, Cambridge, Mass., 1855 (Box 16, Folder 314)
      - Journal of camping trip to Maine with J.A. Wilder, 1856 (Box 16, Folder 315)
      - Journal, 1863-1870 (Box 16, Folder 316)
      - Spring Journal, 1873, April-May, 1881 (Box 16, Folder 317-318)
      - Journal of Vacation, October 1888 (Box 16, Folder 319)
      - Journal of Eclipse Expedition to South Africa, July 1889-May 1890 (Box 16, Folder 320)
      - Small Notebooks from South African Trip, 1889-1890 (Box 17, Folder 321)
      - Notebooks on Nature: Birds, weather, flowers, 1894, 1895 (Box 17, Folder 322)
      - Diary of Bermuda Trip, November-Dec, 1902 (Box 17, Folder 323)
      - Notebook with few entries, undated (Box 17, Folder 324)
      - Mary Wilder Loomis: Journal, trip through Berkshires, October 1888 (Box 17, Folder 325)
    - Financial
      - E.J. and M. W. Loomis: Detailed expense and account book, 1852-1865, 1866-1876 (Box 17, Folder 326-327)
      - M.W. Loomis: Detailed expense and account book, 1896-1901 (Box 18, Folder 328)
      - E.J. and M. W. Loomis: Detailed expense and account book, 1906-1909 (Box 18, Folder 329)
      - E.J. and M.W. Loomis: Small diary account-books, 1856, 1858 (Box 18, Folder 330)
      - E.J. Loomis: Diaries with accounts, 1857, 1858 (Box 18, Folder 331)
      - E.J. Loomis: Diaries with accounts, 1861, 1862 (Box 18, Folder 332)
      - M.W. Loomis: Diaries with accounts, 1864, 1866 (Box 18, Folder 333)
      - E.J. and M.W. Loomis: Almanac used as account book, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 334)
      - E.J. and M.W. Loomis: Note and expense book for trip to Lancaster, N.H., 1895 (Box 18, Folder 335)
      - E.J. and M.W. Loomis: Small Notebooks mainly of finances, 1901-1903; 1905-1908; 1907-1910 (Box 19, Folder 336)
      - Taxes: Cambridge, Washington, 1859-1864, 1899, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 337)
      - U.S. Treasury Bonds, 1878-1880 (Box 19, Folder 338)
      - Bank Accounts: Bank books, corresp., lists of savings deposits, 1879-1911 (Box 19, Folder 339)
      - Life Insurance: New England Mutual Policy: Printed matter, corresp., and receipts, 1866-1912 (Box 19, Folder 340)
      - Insurance: Life and property, 1857-1890 (Box 19, Folder 341)
      - Real Estate Transactions, Missouri, Washington, 1868-1872, 1903-1904 (Box 19, Folder 342)
      - Rentals: Church pew, p.o. box, other, 1860-1864, 1860-1862, 1876, 1901 (Box 19, Folder 343)
      - South African diamond: documents, 1890, 1895 (Box 19, Folder 344)
      - Doctor's bills, 1858-1863 (Box 19, Folder 345)
      - Room and board bills, 1862-1863, 1899-1900 (Box 19, Folder 346)
      - E.J. and M.W. Loomis: 3 grocery credit books, 1857-1866 (Box 19, Folder 347)
      - Receipted grocery bills, 1858-1860; 1863, 1899-1900 (Box 19, Folder 348)
      - Coal, electric and water bills, 1863, 1899-1900 (Box 19, Folder 349)
      - Misc. bills: books, clothing, household goods, hardware, carpentry, mainly 1858-1863, and 1888-1900 (Box 19, Folder 350)
      - Subscriptions: Journals, newspapers, societies, 1858-1863, 1882-1900 (Box 19, Folder 351)
      - E.J. Loomis: debts, credits, donations, advances on pay, sales, misc. notes, list of corresp., 1866-1910 (Box 19, Folder 352)
      - M.A.W. Loomis: Documents re death: will, estate, cemetery lot and gravestone, 1899-1911 (Box 19, Folder 353)
      - E.J. Loomis will, 1883, 1908 (Box 19, Folder 354)
    - E.J. Loomis: Education
      - Lawrence Scientific School, Cambridge, Mass. Notes on Prof. Asa Gray's botany lectures, April-May 1854 (Box 20, Folder 355)
      - Lawrence Scientific School, Cambridge, Mass. Notes on Prof. Louis Agassiz's lectures on geology and zoology, 1854, 1855 (Box 20, Folder 356)
    - E.J. Loomis: Professional
      - Nautical Almanac and U.S. Navy Observatory: Papers re E. Loomis employment there, 1871-1900 (Box 20, Folder 357)
      - Nautical Almanac, U.S. Naval Observatory: Report by C.H. Davis; Report by Nourse, Paper by Simon Newcomb, and misc. notes on its history, 1852, 1872, 1879 (Box 20, Folder 358)
      - Nautical Almanac and U.S. Naval Observatory: Printed matter on history of (mainly newspapers), 1853-1928 (Box 20, Folder 359)
      - Nautical Almanac and U.S. Naval Observatory: Blank forms and official stationery, 19th century (Box 20, Folder 360)
      - South Africa: for publicity and other material, 1889-1890
        See: REL USS Pensacola trip; See: D.P. Todd: subj. file: 1889 Eclipse
      - E.J.L.: Notes, sketches, and souvenirs from South African trip, 1889-1890 (Box 20, Folder 362)
    - E.J. Loomis: sketches, undated (Box 20, Folder 363)
    - E.J.L.: Misc. notes and lists, mostly undated (Box 20, Folder 364)
    - E.J.L.-M.W.L. Homes and furnishings list of addresses; printed matter, etc. on homes, Cambridge, Mass., and Washington, D.C., 1851-1900, 1857-1896 (Box 20, Folder 365)
    - E.J.L.-M.W.L. Houses; Plans by Millicent Todd for an Amherst house, 1892-1896 and undated (Box 20, Folder 366)
    - E.J.L.-M.W.L. Homes and furnishings printed matter, plans, etc., on Cleveland Park, Wash., and moving to Amherst, 1896-1900 (Box 20, Folder 367)
    - Mary Wilder Loomis: early possessions: music books, Bible (now in Concord), 1847-1851, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 368)
    - Mary W. Loomis: household inventories, 1884-1909 (Box 20, Folder 369)
    - Mary A. Wilder Loomis: pocket diaries and address books, 1866, 1883-1888, and undated (Box 20, Folder 370)
    - Mary Wilder Loomis: miscellaneous printed matter, lists, recipes, etc., 1869-1907 (Box 20, Folder 371)
    - E.J.L.: Programs, invitations, academic and literary societies, 1860-[1880-1890]-1908 (Box 20, Folder 372)
    - E.J.L.-M.W.L.: programs, invitations and similar printed matter, 1859-1910 (Box 20, Folder 373)
    - E.J. and M.W. Loomis: celebration of golden wedding anniversary, July 13, 1903 (Box 20, Folder 374)
    - E.J. Loomis: 80th birthday scrapbook, November 11, 1908
      See: folio 36
    - Mary Wilder Loomis: death, cards, notices, funeral arrangements, September 20, 1910 (Box 20, Folder 375)
    - Eben Jenks Loomis: death, obituaries, December 2, 1912 (Box 20, Folder 376)
    - Sketches by unidentified persons, some probably Loomis's, undated (Box 20, Folder 377)
    - "Persons" File: Information on E.J.L. and M.W.L. correspondents (mainly clippings), undated (Box 20, Folder 378)
    - Chase, Persis F.: Writings of, 1882-1891 (Box 21, Folder 379)
    - Newcomb, Simon and family, biographical information on, 1882-1909 (Box 21, Folder 380)
    - Shoemaker, Dr. William, poetry and biographical information, 1877-1898 (Box 21, Folder 381)
    - Writings of others: some copied by E.J.L. and M.W.L., mostly undated (Box 21, Folder 382)
    - Loomis, Mary Alden (Mrs. Eben J. Loomis): mounted dried sea mosses and directions to make a moss wreath, Circa 1872 (Box 21A, Folder 383-386)
- MARY WILDER LOOMIS (1833-1910), 1855-1910; Series III; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)